[indistinct conversations]
[beeps]
[door unlocks]
[computer whirring]
[beeps]
[door whooshing]
[air hisses]
[clicks]
[man] I DARESAY YOU'VE INSPECTED
MORE MODERN FACILITIES
IN YOUR TRAVELS, BUT, UH--
GRIFFIN.
DON'T COME IN HERE.
DR. SEBERG, WHAT'S WRONG?
OH, MY GOD.
[shoes shuffling]
[shuffles]
HEY.
CHEER UP.WHY?
UH, 'CAUSE IT'S BETTER
TO BE HAPPY THAN SAD.
I'M NOT SAD.YOU'RE VERY SAD.
YOU'VE BEEN SAD FOR MONTHS,
EVER SINCE, UH--WHAT, IS THIS SOME SORT
OF THERAPY SESSION?
DID YOU BRING TISSUE
IN CASE YOU MAKE ME CRY?
THERE WE GO. ZING OF ANGER--
GETS THE BLOOD UP.
THAT'S A GOOD START.IS THIS WHAT YOU CAME HERE FOR--
TO ZING ME?
BECAUSE I'VE GOT
PAPERWORK TO DO.JANE, CALL FOR YOU. THEY SAY
IT'S EXTREMELY URGENT. LINE TWO.
OOH.
[picks up telephone receiver]
[clears throat]
THIS IS JANE.
[woman] Good morning, Mr. Jane.
MY NAME IS DR. ALICIA SEBERG.
I GATHER FROM A BRIEF SEARCH
ON THE INTERNET
THAT YOU'RE THE BEST DETECTIVE
IN MY IMMEDIATE VICINITY.
OH. WELL, UM...
YOU FLATTER ME, BUT, UH,
I'M NOT ACTUALLY A DETECTIVE.
I NEED
YOUR PROFESSIONAL ASSISTANCE.
Please come immediately.
I'VE BEEN MURDERED.
[helicopter whirring]
WHOO!
THAT WAS FUN!
[Patrick] WHOO!
AGENT LISBON! CBI!
MA'AM, SIR,
PLEASE FOLLOW ME.
ALL RIGHT!
AGENT LISBON.
AND YOU ARE...
I'M THIS GUY--
PATRICK JANE. CONSULTANT?
OKAY, TERESA, PATRICK,
GLAD TO MEET YOU BOTH.
I'M DEAN HARKEN, CALIFORNIA
DISEASE CONTROL AUTHORITY.
NICE TO MEET YOU.YEAH, WE HAVE
A POTENTIAL CODE RED
VIRUS OUTBREAK SITUATION HERE.
THIS FACILITY
IS UNDER C.D.C.A. CONTROL,
AS PER
STATE EMERGENCY PROTOCOLS.
THOUSANDS OF PEOPLE MIGHT DIE IF
WE DON'T GET THIS RIGHT, OKAY?
WE'VE BEEN APPRISED
OF THE BASIC--NOW SHE'S DENYING IT, OF COURSE,
BUT THIS SITUATION'S
ALMOST CERTAINLY RESULTED
FROM AN ERROR BY DR. SEBERG.
THERE'S NO CRIMINALITY
INVOLVED,
SO YOU'RE NOT REALLY
NEEDED HERE.PROBABLY,
BUT WE'RE GONNA HAVE--
AS A PROFESSIONAL COURTESY, I'M
GONNA LET YOU INTO THE FACILITY.
I'M HAPPY FOR YOU GUYS
TO OBSERVE AND GATHER EVIDENCE,
AS LONG AS YOU REMEMBER
THAT C.D.C.A. IS BIG DOG HERE.
OUR INVESTIGATION HAS PRIORITY.
NOW ARE WE COOL WITH THAT?
ABSOLUTELY.
CAN I SEE
YOUR I.D. ALSO?
SURE.
THANK YOU... DEAN.
NO PICTURE. THAT'S A SHAME.
YOU'RE A GOOD-LOOKING MAN.
SCOTT PRICE,
I MANAGE THIS FACILITY
FOR ZITEK
BIOSYSTEMS DIVISION.
RIGHT OFF THE BAT,
LET ME ASSURE YOU
THAT WE AS A COMPANY ARE
110% COMMITTED TO GIVING YOU
THE BEST POSSIBLE COOPERATION.THANK YOU, MR. PRICE. SHALL WE?
THERE'S A SENSE OF URGENCY HERE.
AH, YES, OF COURSE.
LISBON, JANE, DR. EDMUNDS,
HEAD OF RESEARCH HERE.
HE'LL TAKE YOU
TO THE RELEASE INCIDENT.
PRICE, COME WITH ME.
THANK YOU FOR COMING
SO QUICKLY.
WHAT EXACTLY IS IT
THAT YOU DO HERE?
BIOWARFARE.
WITH MODERN TECHNOLOGY,
ANTHRAX, BOTULISM,
BUBONIC PLAGUE,
EVEN COBRA VENOM ALL HAVE
STRONG WEAPONIZING POTENTIAL.
IT'S A GROWING FIELD.
A LOT OF EXCITING DEVELOPMENTS.
YOU DEVELOP WAYS OF KILLING
PEOPLE IN LARGE NUMBERS.
TO THE CONTRARY. WE DEVELOP
ANTIDOTES, WAYS TO COMBAT
THE THINGS THAT KILL
LARGE NUMBERS OF PEOPLE.
HERE WE ARE.
[computer whirring]
[beeps]
[door unlocks]FOLLOW ME.
120.
DARLING. IS THIS MR. JANE?
YES. HOW ARE YOU FEELING?THE SAME.
INTERESTING IMPROVEMENT
IN CARDIAC RATE, THOUGH.
MY METABOLISM'S TRYING TO
FIGHT BACK WITH ADRENALINE.
GOOD MORNING, MR. JANE.
HI.
AGENT LISBON, CBI.
YOU MIND WRITING THIS DOWN
FOR US?
SOMEONE OPENED THIS FLASK
AND LEFT IT UNDER THE TANK.
IT CONTAINS AN AIRBORNE FORM
OF CRYPTOHANSA B STRAIN.
IT'S
AN ENGINEERED SUPERVIRUS.
IF IT ESCAPED FROM THIS ROOM,
IT WOULD KILL
EVERY VERTEBRATE CREATURE
WITHIN A QUARTER-MILE RADIUS.
IT ATTACKS THE RED BLOOD CELLS,
GRADUALLY STOPS THEM
FROM DELIVERING OXYGEN.
THE VICTIM... DIES FROM
SUFFOCATION OR A HEART ATTACK,
DEPENDING ON
THEIR PHYSICAL CONDITION.
HOW LONG AFTER EXPOSURE?
WE ESTIMATE ANYWHERE
FROM TWO TO SIX HOURS.
SO YOU COULD DIE AT ANY TIME?YES.
HARKEN SAYS YOU DID THIS
YOURSELF--TRAGIC ERROR.
HE'S A BUREAUCRAT. HE'S LOOKING
FOR THE EASY ANSWER.
IT TAKES FOUR DISTINCT STEPS
TO REMOVE A CAP
FROM ONE OF THESE FLASKS,
AND WE NEVER OPEN A FLASK
OUTSIDE OF THE TANK.
THAT'S JUST BASIC.
I CAN ASSURE YOU BOTH,
I HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH THIS.
BUT THIS WAS NO MISTAKE.
WHOEVER DID THIS WANTED ME DEAD.
EVERYBODY KNOWS I TAKE
THE FIRST SHIFT.
SHE CALLED YOU "DARLING."
YOU BOTH HAVE WEDDING BANDS.
YOU HUSBAND AND WIFE?
YES.
WELL, SHE LOOKS SURPRISED
BECAUSE YOU SEEM
INCREDIBLY CALM AND COOL
FOR A MAN WHOSE WIFE
IS DYING.
HOW WOULD AN ABSENCE OF CALM
AND COOL BE USEFUL TO HER?
GOOD POINT.
CORRECT ME IF I'M WRONG,
BUT FOR THE KILLER TO OPEN
THE FLASK,
THEY WOULD HAVE TO EXPOSE
THEMSELVES TO THE VIRUS,
IN WHICH CASE, THEY WOULD BE
DYING OR POSSIBLY DEAD ALREADY.
NO, THERE'S AN ANTIDOTE.
IT'S AN ENZYME COMPOUND.
IF TAKEN BEFORE EXPOSURE,
IT PREVENTS INFECTION.
I ASSUME WHOEVER DID THIS
TOOK A DOSE.
COULDN'T YOU J--NO, I CAN'T TAKE IT NOW.
THE ANTIDOTE ONLY WORKS IF TAKEN
BEFOREEXPOSURE, AS I SAID.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TAKE IT BEFORE,
JUST AS A PRECAUTION?
THE SIDE EFFECTS OF REGULAR USE
ARE FAR TOO SEVERE.
WHO ELSE HAD ACCESS
TO THE VIRUS FLASK?
THE ONLY PEOPLE ALLOWED
IN THE LAB ARE CLIFF AND I,
WELKS, NASH AND TRIPP,
OUR COLLEAGUES.
WE HAVE A STATE-OF-THE-ART
BIOMETRIC SECURITY SYSTEM,
AS YOU CAN SEE.
SO YOUR HUSBAND
OR ONE OF THE THREE COLLEAGUES
IS THE KILLER.
SORRY. UH, WILLBE THE KILLER.
JANE.
I'M JUST... MM.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT. THAT IS
THE UNAVOIDABLE CONCLUSION.
YES.
WHERE ARE
THE OTHER THREE NOW?
HARKEN IS HAVING THEM
FILL OUT AN ACCIDENT REPORT.WE'RE GONNA NEED TO SPEAK
TO THEM.
OOH, THIS IS
A GOOD ONE, EH?
GOOD?
WELL, INTERESTING. UNIQUE.
IF YOU'RE A JADED, GHOULISH
ADVENTURE SEEKER.
GHOULISH? LISTEN, IF PEOPLE
ARE GONNA KILL EACH OTHER
AND WE HAVE TO CATCH THEM,
I WOULD MUCH RATHER
THEY GO ABOUT IT WITH
SOME KIND OF ORIGINALITY.
[Van Pelt] Boss?HEY, VAN PELT.
I need you to do background
checks on Cliff Edmunds...
[speaking indistinctly]LILITH NASH,
GRIFFIN LATIMER WELKS,
Florian Eric Tripp.
I'm sending you
their details now.
ANYTHING TO BE
LOOKING OUT FOR IN PARTICULAR?
OH, UH, ONE OF THEM RELEASED
A LETHAL SUPERVIRUS
THAT COULD KILL HALF
THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA,
so I guess we're looking for
someone with a prior background
as an evil supervillain.
OKAY.
THAT LAST PART WAS A JOKE.YEAH, WE GET IT.
Later.
HELLO.
HI.
HELLO.HELLO.
[clears throat]
[sighs deeply]
WHAT ARE YOU DOIN'?WHAT DOES IT LOOK LIKE
I'M DOING?
TRYING TO MAKE US NERVOUS?CORRECT. HOW AM I DOING?
DOING WELL.EXCELLENT.
BUT WHY?
ONE OF YOU THREE
MURDERED ALICIA SEBERG,
OR HER HUSBAND DID.
IT'S OUR JOB TO FIND OUT WHO.AND WE'RE IN A HURRY,
AND NERVOUS PEOPLE
ARE EASY TO READ.AND WHAT DO YOU GATHER
FROM ALL THIS READING?
WELL, YOU'RE AN OPEN BOOK.
YOU'RE EXACTLY WHAT
YOU SEEM TO BE--
A STRAIGHT ARROW, A BOY SCOUT.
AM I RIGHT?NO.
I'M WRONG.
THERE'S A HIDDEN SIDE TO YOU.YES, BUT--
WHAT ARE YOU HIDING?NOTHING.
WHAT IS HE HIDING, LILITH?I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT ARE YOUHIDING?I-I'M NOT--
IT WAS YOU, WASN'T IT?ME WHAT?
YOU WERE HAVING AN AFFAIR
WITH ALICIA SEBERG.
WHAT? NO, NOT WITH ME.
NOT WITH YOU.
WITH WHO, THEN?
I OVERSEE EQUIPMENT
AND INVENTORY,
NOT MY COLLEAGUES'
PRIVATE LIVES.
BUT SHE WASHAVING
AN AFFAIR, HUH?
WHY ELSE WOULD A HUSBAND
HAVE THE MOTIVES TO KILL HER?
AND IF IT WASN'T HER HUSBAND,
IT WAS ONE OF YOU.
WHO WAS IT?
MY GUESS...
KASEEM.[knocks on table]
YES.
DOES HER HUSBAND KNOW?OH, HE KNOWS.
DR. EDMUNDS IS
A KIND, GENTLE MAN.
HE COULDN'T HAVE DONE THIS.
THANK YOU, LILITH, FLORIAN...
GRIFFIN.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL US YOU WERE
HAVING AN AFFAIR
WITH DR. KASEEM HERE?BECAUSE IT ISN'T RELEVANT.
YEAH, WE HAVE
AN HONEST AND OPEN MARRIAGE.
THEY DO.
REALLY?
YOU DON'T MIND?
[Edmunds]
NO, I DON'T MIND AT ALL.
FIDELITY IS SIMPLY
A CULTURAL CONVENTION.
LIKE CLOTHES
AND NOT KILLING PEOPLE.
YOU COULD SAY SO.
COME ON.
IT MUST BUG YOU A LITTLE.
NO. WE LOVE EACH OTHER.
HER HAPPINESS IS MINE.
IT'S NOT LIKE I DON'T HAVE
AFFAIRS MYSELF.
ARE YOU HAVING AN AFFAIR
PRESENTLY?
NO. I'VE BEEN FAR TOO BUSY.
Y-YOU MUST THINK
THIS IS A LITTLE WEIRD.
UH... YEAH... AT FIRST.
BUT HEY. [chuckles]
WHAT AN ELOQUENT PHRASE
THAT IS.
[telephone rings]
OH! ISABEL. THANK GOD.
[ring]
[choking][ring]
Mom?
Mom, I got Dad's message.
[mouths words] Is it true?
YES, IT'S TRUE.
[crying] No.
No, no, it can't be!
OH, THIS IS A PICKLE,
ISN'T IT?
[crying] OH, BABY, DON'T CRY.
DON'T CRY.
[continues crying] How can you
tell me not to cry?
Of course I'm going to cry.
Is there something you can do?
There has to be something!
LISTEN TO ME.
WE DON'T HAVE MUCH TIME,
SO WE MUSTN'T WASTE IT
WEEPING AND WAILING, OKAY?
Okay.GOOD.
HOW'S SCHOOL GOING? DID YOU GET
YOUR CALCULUS GRADE UP?
I got a 95 on my last test.
OH, WELL DONE.
YOU KEEP THAT UP.
A-AND WHAT ABOUT THAT BOY, ANDY?
HOW'S THAT GOING?
Oh, he's a jerk. [sniffles]
I don't see him anymore.
WELL, I MUST SAY,
I'M GLAD TO HEAR THAT.
I DIDN'T LIKE
THE SOUND OF HIM.
[coughs]
[choking]
I LOVE YOU SO MUCH.
[whispers] YOU'RE THE BEST THING
I EVER DID.
AND I AM SO... PROUD OF YOU.
[crying] Mom.
SHH, SHH, SHH!
WHEN I'M GONE,
YOU MUSTN'T WASTE TIME
BEING SAD.
A LITTLE WHILE IS OKAY,
BUT NOT TOO LONG.
YOU BE BRAVE.
AND BE HAPPY.
[crying]
BYE, BABY.
[sobbing] Mom!
Mom!BYE, BABY.
No, Mom!
[gasping]
GOOD-BYE, MY LOVE.
I LOVE YOU, DARLING.
GOOD-BYE.
[gasping]
[clank]
[chokes]
[sobbing]
SHE'S GONE, BABY.
SHE'S GONE.
[continues sobbing]
[indistinct conversations]
SHE'S DEAD?
[Lisbon] YES.
I'M, UH...
I'M SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
MY PEOPLE AND I WILL GET PREPPED
FOR THE DECONTAMINATION
PROCEDURE.HOW DOES THAT WORK?
IT'S A LOW-INTENSITY
MICRO-RADIATION BATH
BUILT IN FOR THIS EVENTUALITY.
THE CHAMBER IS IRRADIATED.
THE VIRUS IS DESTROYED.
ALICIA'S BODY'S NOT HARMED.
HOW LONG UNTIL WE CAN EXAMINE
THE CRIME SCENE?WHOA.
IT'S NOT A CRIME SCENE UNTIL
YOU KNOW THERE'S A CRIME, RIGHT?
WELL, YOU DON'T KNOW
THERE'S BEEN A MURDER HERE.
WHERE'S YOUR EVIDENCE?ALICIA'S SEBERG'S WORD.
WHY WOULD SHE LIE?SHE HAD A BRAIN FREEZE.
SHE SCREWED UP,
AND SHE CAN'T ADMIT THE FACT.
IT HAPPENS. I'VE BEEN WORKING
THIS BEAT FOR A LONG TIME.
I'VE SEEN THE SAME DENIAL,
SAME CERTAINTY.
IT'S HUMAN NATURE.I DISAGREE. I BELIEVE HER.
I'M CALLING THIS IN
AS A HOMICIDE.
AND I'M SORRY IF THIS
COMPLICATES YOUR WORK,
BUT IT'S MY JOB.THAT'S FINE. OKAY.
DOING YOUR JOB.
BUT THIS IS STILL
A LIVE OUTBREAK,
AND I'M IN CHARGE HERE.
YOU WANNA MAKE A MURDER CASE,
WE'LL DEAL WITH THE SUSPECTS
AS PER C.D.C.A. PROTOCOLS.
ABSOLUTELY.
[Van Pelt]
UNTIL THE SUMMER OF '08,
SEBERG, EDMUNDS, NASH AND TRIPP
ALL WORKED TOGETHER
AT THE NORTHERN CALIFORNIA
TECHNOLOGY INSTITUTE
BIOCHEMISTRY DEPARTMENT.[clicking keys]
SEBERG AND EDMUNDS
LEFT ABRUPTLY--
SOME KIND OF LEGAL DISPUTE.
OKAY, CHO AND I
WILL CHECK IT OUT.
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN CONVICTED
OF A CRIMINAL OFFENSE?
NO.
ARE YOU NOW OR HAVE YOU
EVER BEEN A MEMBER
OF A TERRORIST ORGANIZATION?THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
THIS ISRIDICULOUS.[lowered voice]
JUST LET IT GO.
LET'S HAVE SOME QUIET
BACK THERE, HUH?
NOW, MR. TRIPP, PLEASE--WHY?
WHY?
WHAT DIFFERENCE
DOES OUR SILENCE MAKE?
SILENT OR NOT, YOU'RE STILL
WASTING EVERYBODY'S TIME
WITH THIS NONSENSE.YOU GUYS CALLED THIS HOMICIDE,
SO NOW WE HAVE
TO RUN THE PAPERWORK.
THAT'S HOW IT WORKS.STILL A WASTE OF TIME.
I THOUGHT I MADE THE DEAL
CLEAR TO YOU GUYS.
YOU REALLY WANNA MESS
WITH THE C.D.C.A.?ABSOLUTELY NOT. I APOLOGIZE
FOR MY COLLEAGUE'S RUDENESS--
NO, SHE DOESN'T.
I RETRACT THAT APOLOGY.
SHOW SOME METTLE, LISBON.
YOU KNOW AS WELL AS I DO,
IF I HAVE TEN MINUTES
WITH THESE PEOPLE,
I WILL GET THE TRUTH, IF THERE'S
ANY USEFUL TRUTH WORTH HAVING.EXCUSE US. [mouths word]
YES, EXCUSE US.
WE HAVE TO HAVE A CHAT.
[lowers voice] COOL IT,
ALL RIGHT? THAT IS AN ORDER.
[lowers voice] OKAY. JUST RELAX.
I'M WORKING THE CASE.
LET ME EXPLAIN
SOMETHING TO YOU.MM-HMM.
THIS IS POLITICS.
THE C.D.C.A. IS RICH,
MEAN AND WELL CONNECTED.
THE CBI IN COMPARISON
ARE LIKE POOR ORPHANS.
WE CAN'T MAKE ENEMIES
OUT OF THEM.
WE NEED TO COOPERATE
WITH THIS MAN.
HE IRKS ME.SAY IT. "I UNDERSTAND."
HMM. [mutters]
GO. FIND YOURSELF
A VENDING MACHINE.
BUY YOURSELF A CANDY BAR
AND COME BACK
WHEN YOU'RE READY
TO PLAY NICE.GIVE ME A DOLLAR AND I WILL.
[bill crinkling]
YOU'RE PAYING ME BACK.
CARRY ON.
[man] OH, MY LORD.
THAT'S TERRIBLE.
AND YOU SUSPECT FOUL PLAY
OF SOME KIND?[Cho] UH, PROFESSOR,
DR. SEBERG AND HER HUSBAND
WORKED HERE AT THE INSTITUTE
UNTIL '08,
AS DID FLORIAN TRIPP
AND LILITH NASH.
IS THAT CORRECT?YES. BRILLIANT RESEARCH TEAM.
WE WERE VERY SORRY TO LOSE THEM.
MONEY, YOU KNOW? WE TRIED
TO HOLD THEM TO THEIR CONTRACT,
BUT ZITEK THREATENED
A LAWSUIT,
SO THEY LEFT
RATHER UNDER A CLOUD.
BUT EDMUNDS AND SEBERG
AS A COUPLE--DID THEY GET ALONG?OH, I THINK SO, DESPITE ALL.
DESPITE ALL WHAT?
WELL, UH, I DON'T LIKE TO LISTEN
TO THAT SORT OF GOSSIP,
BUT, UH, ONE HEARS THINGS.LIKE?
EDMUNDS WAS QUITE
THE LADIES' MAN.
HE HAD AFFAIRS.SO I GATHER.
QUITE THE DRAMA SOMETIMES.
DRAMA OF WHAT TYPE?FIREWORKS, AS IT WERE,
YOU KNOW.
BUT AS I SAY,
I DON'T PAY ATTENTION.
ANYBODY YOU KNOW WHO DID--
PAY ATTENTION?
AH, I BELIEVE
ONE OF OUR GRAD STUDENTS
IN THE ASTROPHYSICS DEPARTMENT
WAS, UH, INVOLVED.
NAME?GRETA SKYE.
HOW LONG DOES THIS
DECONTAMINATION TAKE?
ANOTHER HOUR.
HMM.
DON'T TOUCH THAT, PLEASE.
THIS IS A MURDER INVESTIGATION.
I CAN TOUCH WHAT I WANT.
YOU HAVE A PROBLEM
WITH THAT?
THERE'S DANGEROUS STUFF
IN HERE, THAT'S ALL.
[clank]
[chewing] I LIKE WHAT
THEY'RE DOING THESE DAYS.
THEY'RE MAKING
REGULAR CANDY BARS,
ONLY WITH DARK CHOCOLATE.
YOU TRIED THAT?NO.
YOU--YOU WANT A BITE?
NO, THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
HMM. [chewing] REALLY GOOD.
HI.
CAN YOU HEAR ME?
ISABEL, RIGHT?
Who are you?
MY NAME'S PATRICK JANE.
I'M HERE TO FIND OUT
WHO KILLED YOUR MOTHER.
Good. Kill them, please.
OH, I WISH I WAS ALLOWED
TO DO THAT.
YOU KNOW, YOU SHOULD PROBABLY
STEP AWAY FROM YOUR COMPUTER.
DO YOU HAVE ANY FRIENDS NEARBY? I wanna be with my mother.
YEAH.
I'M SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS.
DO YOU HAVE
A CANDY BAR AROUND AT ALL?
What?
WELL, WE WERE JUST TALKING
CHOCOLATE,
AND IT OCCURRED TO ME THAT
CHOCOLATE WOULD BE GOOD FOR YOU.
ALL THAT EMOTION--
IT WIPES YOU OUT.
AND SUGAR'S GOOD
FOR ENERGY.
My mother is dead.
CHOCOLATE AND GRIEF
IS A GOOD COMBINATION.
YOU SHOULD TRY IT.
IT'LL TASTE SO MUCH... DEEPER,
MORE INTENSE.
EVERYTHING WILL FEEL THAT WAY
FOR A WHILE.
YOU'LL FEEL MORE ALIVE.
YOU SHOULD PROBABLY TRY
TO HANG ON TO THAT FEELING
AS LONG AS YOU CAN.
IT'S A GIFT.
I guess.
I WANT YOU TO DO SOMETHING
FOR ME NOW, ISABEL.
I WANT YOU TO PLEASE
TURN OFF YOUR COMPUTER
AND GO AND TELL A FRIEND
WHAT'S HAPPENED.
YOU DO THAT NOW.
[beep]
OPEN SESAME.
[rapid beeping and whirring]
[beeps]WHOA!
[whooshing]
THAT WASN'T MEANT TO HAPPEN,
WAS IT?
UH-OH.
DO YOU HAVE AN ADVANCED DEGREE
IN ANY OF THE PHYSICAL SCIENCES?
YES.
EXCUSE ME. UH...
SORRY TO INTERRUPT.
WE NEED TO EXPAND
THE POOL OF SUSPECTS.
THE TRICKY LITTLE HIGH-TECH
SCANNERS LET ANYONE IN.
THAT'S NONSENSE.
TRY IT.
[rapid beeping]
[beeps]
[doors whooshing]I'LL BE DAMNED.
SEE? SAME WITH THAT DOOR.
ANYONE AT THIS FACILITY
COULD'VE GOTTEN TO THOSE
LITTLE VIRUS THINGIES--ANYONE.
WHO'S RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE OPERATION
OF THE SECURITY SCANNERS?[Price] I HAVE NO IDEA
HOW THAT COULD HAPPEN.
THAT'S OUTRAGEOUS.IT'S YOUR JOB TO OVERSEE
THE SECURITY SYSTEMS HERE,
ISN'T IT?
NOT THE TECHNICAL ASPECTS,
OBVIOUSLY.
THAT'S CONTRACTED OUT,
BUT I'LL GET RIGHT ON 'EM,
GIVE 'EM A PIECE OF MY MIND,
BELIEVE YOU ME.YOU'RE SHOWING US YOUR PALMS.
IT'S A SUPPLICANT GESTURE,
SUGGESTING
A GUILTY CONSCIENCE.
THAT--THAT'S NOT VALID
OR RELEVANT.
I'M--I'M SIMPLY STATING
THE FACTS. I HAVE NO IDEA
WHY THE SECURITY SYSTEM
DOESN'T WORK.
THE MAN'S RIGHT.
YOU'RE NOT REAL CONVINCING.
I REGRET
THAT'S YOUR OPINION,
BUT I-I HAVE NO CONTROL
OVER THAT.MR. PRICE, YOU'RE UNDER ARREST.
FOR WHAT?LET'S SEE.
FOR ONE,
THE MURDER OF ALICIA SEBERG.
THAT'S ABSURD.
AND FRANKLY, NOT YOUR CALL.OH, IS THAT RIGHT?
YEAH, THIS HOMICIDE
INVESTIGATION IS OURS.
IF WE CAN'T GET ALONG,
I'LL CALL MY FRIENDS AT THE FBI,
GET THEM TO TAKE OVER
FROM YOU.
IN FACT, I WILLDO THAT.
I'M SORRY, LITTLE LADY--
MAYBE YOU SHOULD STEP BACK--
MAY-MAYBE I WAS RIGHT ABOUT
THE SUPPLICANT PALM GESTURE.
YEP.
[engine starts]
[tires screech, siren wailing]
[brakes screeching]
[indistinct conversations]
I... I WANNA TALK
TO MY LAWYER.
YOU HAVE THAT RIGHT,
BUT IF IT DOESN'T--
HAVE YOU EVER SAT IN THE BACK
OF A MILITARY AIRCRAFT
WITH A BLACK HOOD
OVER YOUR HEAD?UH... NO.
WELL, THEN YOU GOT
A NEW EXPERIENCE COMIN',
BECAUSE THAT IS WHERE THIS IS
GOIN' UNLESS YOU START TALKIN'
RIGHT ABOUT NOW!UM... LOOK--
QUIET.
PLEASE.
THE CONTRACTOR SCREWED UP.
THE SOFTWARE GLITCHES
CONSTANTLY,
SO... THEY'RE FIXING IT.
MEANWHILE, THE SYSTEM'S DOWN...
TEMPORARILY.
NOBODY KNEW THE SYSTEM WAS DOWN,
SO IN A WAY,
IT WORKED JUST AS IF
IT WAS UP AND RUNNING...
IN A WAY.HOW LONG WAS IT DOWN FOR?
TWO... MONTHS.
TWO MONTHS?ANYONE AT ALL
COULD ENTER THE LAB--
TERRORISTS, CRAZIES,
THIEVES.
HAVE YOU ANY IDEA
HOW MUCH TROUBLE YOU'RE IN?
THIEVES?
PEOPLE WANNA STEAL GERMS?
CRYPTOHANSA B STRAIN IS A--
IS A MUST-HAVE RESEARCH TOOL.
IT'S HARD TO MAKE.
IT'S WORTH $300,000 A GRAM
IN THE BLACK MARKET.
WOW.ISN'T THAT RIGHT, PRICE?
AND YOU LEFT THE CUPBOARD DOOR
WIDE OPEN.
[chuckles] YOU ARE YEA DEEP
IN TROUBLE, PAL.
YOU THINK ABOUT YOUR SITUATION
FOR A WHILE.
OKAY?
AND WE'LL TALK AGAIN.
YOU KNOW HE DIDN'T
KILL ALICIA SEBERG.
YOU JUST LIKE
SCARING PEOPLE, RIGHT?HEY,
IF THERE WAS A MURDER HERE,
I THINK
HE'S A VERY GOOD SUSPECT.WHY? HE HAS NO INTEREST
IN HER DEATH.
IT COULD ONLY LEAD TO DISCOVERY
OF THE SECURITY BREAKDOWN.WE'LL SEE IF HE HAD
ANY OTHER MOTIVES.
THE SALIENT POINT HERE IS
THAT ANYONE COULD HAVE GOTTEN
TO THOSE FLASKS,
NOT JUST PRICE.
KASEEM COULD HAVE, FOR INSTANCE,
OR YOU COULD HAVE.
YOU WERE ALREADY HERE,
WEREN'T YOU?
FOR AN INVENTORY CHECK?
WHAT TIME DID YOU GET HERE,
EXACTLY?
THE NIGHT BEFORE, RIGHT?YOU REMIND ME.
I WAS GONNA CALL THE FBI,
REPLACE YOU PEOPLE.
AND I WAS GONNA TELL YOU
THAT'S NOT YOUR CALL.
WE'RE HERE ON
THE DIRECT SAY-SO OF THE A.G.
CALL HIM. TELL HIM WE'RE OFF
THE CASE. SEE WHAT HE SAYS.I MIGHT DO THAT.
WE'LL SEE HOW IT GOES,
SHALL WE?
IT'S TIME TO OPEN
THE BIOHAZARD CHAMBER.
OH, THAT SOUNDS FUN,
OPENING THE BIOHAZARD CHAMBER.
SHOULDN'T WE BE
WEARING MASKS OR SOMETHING?
NO VIRUS COULD POSSIBLY
SURVIVE THE RADIATION BATH.
THE VIRUS INSIDE THE FLASKS
ARE STILL ALIVE, OF COURSE.
BUT THE FLASKS
ARE UNBREAKABLE.
THERE'S NO DANGER.
[clicks]
FIVE FLASKS INTACT.
[latches click]
LET'S GET THESE BABIES BACK
IN DEEP FREEZE.
OKAY. WE'RE COPACETIC.
[Lisbon] LET'S SEND
ALICIA SEBERG ON HER WAY.[air whooshes]
DOCTOR, THIS IS
A CRIME SCENE NOW. YOU CAN'T--
[Lisbon] LET HIM STAY.
[woman] OH, MY GOD.
OH, MY GOD.
AND, GRETA, YOU HAD
A SEXUAL RELATIONSHIP
WITH CLIFF EDMUNDS,
THE VICTIM'S HUSBAND,
IS THAT RIGHT?
NO. I MEAN, YES.
IT WASN'T--WELL, YES, I DID.
BUT I DIDN'T.
YOU DON'T THINK I HAD SOMETHING
TO DO WITH KILLING HER?
NO, MA'AM, WE'RE JUST LOOKING
FOR INSIGHT
INTO THEIR RELATIONSHIP.YOU THINK CLIFF KILLED HER.
IS HE THE JEALOUS TYPE?NOT AT ALL.
DID HE EVER SHOW VIOLENCE
TO YOU?
NO, NO. CLIFF IS
A VERY GENTLE SOUL, REALLY.
AND ALICIA'S SUCH
A COOL PERSON.
WE HEARD
THERE WAS TROUBLE.
NO.
WELL... [sighs]
THERE WAS ONE INCIDENT,
BUT IT HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH CLIFF OR ALICIA, REALLY.
PLEASE CONTINUE.
WE'D BEEN SEEING EACH OTHER
FOR A WHILE.
SOMEBODY LEFT A NOTE
FOR ME,
PUSHED UNDER BY DOOR
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT.
BASICALLY,
IT SAID I WAS A WHORE
AND I SHOULD STAY AWAY
FROM CLIFF.
IT WAS VERY UGLY.
IT WAS ANONYMOUS, OF COURSE.
WHO DO YOU THINK
SENT THE NOTE?I THOUGHT AT FIRST IT WAS
ALICIA SEBERG, NATURALLY.
BUT IT TURNS OUT SHE WASN'T
EVEN IN THE COUNTRY
ON THE NIGHT IN QUESTION.WHO'S YOUR NEXT BEST GUESS?
UM, THE ONE TIME I WENT
TO SEE CLIFF AT WORK,
THERE WAS A LAB ASSISTANT.
SHE GAVE ME THIS GLARE
LIKE A DEATH RAY,
AND I THOUGHT MAYBE IT WAS HER.WHAT'S HER NAME?
LILITH NASH.
THE QUESTION IS WHY NOW?
WHAT WAS IT THAT TRIGGERED
THE KILLING? WHAT CHANGED?
WHAT'S THE ANSWER?
[lowers voice] WELL, FOR
ONE THING, HARKEN SHOWED UP.YOU THINK HARKEN DID THIS?
OOH, I'D LIKE THAT.
BUT WHAT'S HIS MOTIVE?
[cell phone rings]
VAN PELT.
Boss, Cho and Rigsby found
an ex-lover
of the vic's husband.
SHE THINKS LILITH NASH SENT HER
A MENACING NOTE.
INTERESTING.So I dug deeper.
NASH IS CLEAN
UNDER HER CURRENT NAME
BUT HAD A BRIEF MARRIAGE
IN CANADA IN '96, '97.
Under that name, Lilith Blaum,
in '99, still in Canada,
she had a restraining order
taken out against her
BY HER EX-HUSBAND
AND SUBSEQUENTLY
SPENT FOUR MONTHS
IN A SECURE MENTAL INSTITUTE.WELL, THAT COULD HAPPEN
TO ANYONE.
UH, VAN PELT,
COULD YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
COULD YOU CALL CHO AND RIGSBY
AND HAVE THEM GET OUT HERE
AS QUICK AS POSSIBLE?WHY?
I GOT A HUNCH
WE'RE GONNA NEED 'EM.OKAY.
Thank you.WILL DO.
LET'S GO TALK TO NASH.MEH.
WHAT?
I THINK SHE'S GOOD FOR IT.AH, SHE'S NUTS.
SHE'S GOT A NUTTY LITTLE
SECRET CRUSH ON THE BOSS,
KILLS THE WIFE.SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
SHE DID SEEM NERVOUS,
BUT WHY KILL NOW?
AND WHY WOULD SHE USE
THE VIRUS?I DON'T KNOW.
LET'S GO AND ASK HER.
UGH, IF YOU WANT TO.
YOU KNOW,
YOU'RE JUST RESISTING NASH
BECAUSE YOU DIDN'T PEG HER
RIGHT AWAY AS THE ONE.
NO, I'M RESISTING NASH BECAUSE,
UH, SHE ISN'T THE ONE.
BUT IF YOU WANNA GO TALK TO HER,
LET'S GO TALK TO HER.
BUT WHATEVER YOU DO,
DO NOT TELL HARKEN.
WHY NOT? IT'S PROCEDURE.
FIG FOR PROCEDURE.
HE'LL STOMP ALL OVER HER.
SHE'LL CLAM UP. YOU'LL GET
NOTHING BUT A WASTE OF TIME.I'M TELLING HARKEN.
[sighs deeply]
OKAY.
[sighs]
NASH, COME WITH ME.
NOW.
THANK YOU.
STAND THERE.
[door closes]
[clank]
LISTEN CLOSELY
AND PLEASE TELL THE TRUTH.
IS THERE A WAY OUT OF HERE
THAT AVOIDS THE MAIN GATES?
A BACK WAY OUT?YES.
WHERE?
WALK A MILE NORTH.
THERE'S A CULVERT
THAT GOES UNDER THE FENCE
HALFWAY ALONG
THE NORTHEAST PROPERTY LINE.
EXCELLENT.
NOW... TELL THE TRUTH.
DID YOU EVER GO
BY THE NAME LILITH BLAUM?
YES.
DID YOU SPEND TIME
IN A MENTAL ASYLUM?
YES.
DO YOU HAVE A SECRET CRUSH
ON CLIFF EDMUNDS?
YES.
DID YOU KILL ALICIA SEBERG?
NO.
I BELIEVE YOU,
BUT I KNOW HOW
HARKEN'S THOUGHTS RUN.
A WAY TO BLAME YOU
WILL BE FOUND.
I REPEAT. I KNOW HOW
HARKEN'S THOUGHTS RUN.
A WAY TO BLAME YOU
WILL BE FOUND. DO YOU HEAR ME?YES.
EXCELLENT.
[door opens]
GO.
[clears throat]
[door opens]
DID LILITH NASH
COME BACK IN HERE?
NO.
UH, THAT'S ODD.
WHERE'S LILITH NASH?
UH, SHE LEFT WITH--
YOU DON'T NEED TO WORRY
ABOUT HER.
SHE'S NOT GUILTY.
AND HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT?BECAUSE I ASKED HER.
SHE TOLD ME.
UH-HUH. AND WHERE IS SHE NOW?UM... I DON'T KNOW.
SECURITY.
[blinds rattle]
[siren wailing]
SHE'S NOT IN HER ROOM.
SHE'S NOWHERE TO BE FOUND.
OH, YOU PEOPLE ARE OVERREACTING.
I'M SURE SHE'S NO DANGER.
SHE'S MENTALLY UNSTABLE
AND PROBABLY A KILLER,
BUT YOU'RE SURE SHE'S NO DANGER.
WELL, THAT'S REASSURING.WELL, EVEN IF SHE IS
THOSE THINGS,
AND I DON'T SAY THAT SHE IS,
THEN SHE'S DONE HER WORST
ALREADY.MR. HARKEN!
WE HAVE A CODE RED.
WHAT'S A CODE RED?WHAT? NO.
OH, NO.
OH.
ANYONE WITHIN A QUARTER-MILE
RADIUS OF THIS FLASK
IS GONNA BE DEAD WITHIN
THE NEXT FOUR TO SIX HOURS.
BUT I PUT THE FLASKS
IN THE SAFE.
SHE MUST HAVE GOTTEN
INTO THE SAFE SOMEHOW.W-- H-HOW IS THAT POSSIBLE?
[indistinct conversations]
[click]
WHAT WAS THAT?
A BEAKER FELL.WHAT?
THERE'S ONLY ONE MISSING.
THAT'S A RELIEF, ANYHOW.
BUT HOW DID SHE DO IT?
NEVER MIND HOW. SHE'S DONE IT.
WHAT DO WE DO NOW?
WELL, THERE'S NOTHING
WE CANDO.
IN THE NEXT FOUR HOURS,
WE'LL ALL BE DEAD.[latches click]
[lowers voice]
TELL ME THE TRUTH.
THIS IS A TRICK RIGHT?
NO. WHY WOULD I DO
SOMETHING LIKE THAT?
WHAT WOULD BE THE POINT?SWEAR ON YOUR CHILD'S GRAVE.
YOU KNOW I DON'T DO THAT,
NOT FOR ANYTHING.
OH, MY GOD.
THIS IS A DRILL, RIGHT?UH, THIS IS NOT A DRILL.
THIS IS--THIS IS THE REAL THING.
I'M SORRY.
[all murmuring]
LISTEN UP.
WE HAVE A FEW HOURS LEFT.
BUT WE'LL KEEP
THIS VIRUS CONTAINED HERE.
NOBODY LEAVES THIS FACILITY.
AND THEN WHAT?
WE GET BURIED IN THE DESERT?
THE AIR FORCE WILL DROP
INCENDIARY BOMBS
ON THE FACILITY,
BURN THE VIRUS OUT.
YOUR NEXT OF KIN
WILL BE INFORMED.
LIKE I SAY,
WE HAVE A FEW HOURS LEFT,
SO WE ALL SHOULD MAKE
OUR ARRANGEMENTS
AND SAY OUR PRAYERS
AS BEST WE CAN.
MAKE YOUR PHONE CALLS.
MAY GOD HAVE MERCY
ON OUR SOULS.
[indistinct conversations]
[speaking inaudibly]
[cell phone rings]
HEY, BOSS. WE'RE ABOUT
FIVE MINUTES FROM YOUR LOCATION.
Cho, listen.
JANE AND I HAVE BEEN EXPOSED
TO THE VIRUS,
AND IT LOOKS LIKE
WE MIGHT DIE SOON.
OKAY.
SO I WANNA THANK YOU AND RIGSBY
AND VAN PELT.
It's been an honor
working with you.
I NEED YOU TO CALL
MY BROTHER TOMMY.
HIS NUMBER IS
IN MY DESK DIARY.
IT'S UNDER
TOWN AND COUNTRY ELECTRICAL.
TELL HIM THAT I LOVE HIM
AND THAT I FORGIVE HIM
FOR WHATEVER
AND THAT, UM, HE NEEDS TO MAKE
PEACE WITH HIS BROTHERS.
It's my last dying wish.
You tell him that.
WILL DO.
OKAY. GOOD-BYE.
UH, WAIT. I-I WANTED
TO TALK TO THEM ALSO.
SORRY.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
THAT'S A FINE FAREWELL.
I FEARED THAT YOU'D BECOME
TEARFUL AND INCOHERENT, BUT NO.
SUCCINCT.
NOBLE. BRAVO.
UH-HUH.
DON'T YOU HAVE ANYBODY
YOU WANNA CALL
BESIDES CHO AND RIGSBY?
NO.
AND IF I WEREDYING,
I'D WANNA CALL YOU,
BUT... YOU'RE ALREADY HERE.
SO THERE'S NO NEED.
ME?
HMM?
WHAT WOULD YOU SAY?
OH...
UH... WAIT--
WAIT A MINUTE. IF?
IFI WAS DYING?YEAH, YOU'RE NOT REALLY DYING.
I WROTE A LABEL
AND PUT IT ON AN EMPTY FLASK,
AND THEN I CONVINCED
POOR LILITH NASH TO RUN AWAY.
I FEEL KIND OF BAD ABOUT IT--YOU SON OF A BITCH.
BUT JUST--JUST WAIT.
JUST PLEASE. BE STILL. CHO?
THIS IS JANE. PLEASE DISREGARD
LISBON'S LAST MESSAGE.
I TRICKED HER. MY BAD.
[whispers] I'M SO SORRY.
[normal voice] ARE YOU AT
THE CULVERT? OKAY, GOOD. WAIT.
THERE'LL BE SOME PEOPLE
COMING YOUR WAY SOON. BYE.
YOU'RE SICK.
WHY WOULD YOU DO THIS
TO ME?
TWO REASONS--FIRSTLY, TO CATCH
THE KILLER OF ALICIA SEBERG,
THE KILLER WHO IS NOT
POOR LILITH NASH.
THE KILLER WHO,
YOU MAY RECALL,
TOOK A DOSE OF THE ANTIDOTE
IN ORDER TO SURVIVE
EXPOSURE TO THE VIRUS. YES?YES...
THE KILLER WHO BELIEVES
THAT HE OR SHE
IS THE ONLY ONE
THAT ISN'T GOING TO DIE. YES?YES.
SO THEY HAVE TO GET OUT OF HERE
BEFORE WEDIE,
OR ELSE THEY'LL BE BURNT
TO A CRISP BY THE AIR FORCE.
THEIR HANDS ARE TIED.
THEY HAVE TO TRY TO ESCAPE,
THUS REVEALING THEMSELVES TO US
WITH PRECISION AND CLARITY
OF A MATHEMATICAL EQUATION.AND REASON NUMBER TWO?
THE SECOND
AND MOST IMPORTANT REASON
IS DOESN'T IT FEEL GREAT
TO GET YOUR LIFE BACK?
DON'T YOU FEEL GOOD
RIGHT NOW?
DON'T YOU FEEL HAPPY
TO BE ALIVE?
NO!
OH, I KNOW YOU DO.
YOU KNOW YOU DO.
IF REASON NUMBER ONE DOES NOT
PAN OUT VERY, VERY SOON,
I THINK I'M GONNA PUNCH YOU
IN THE NOSE.
FORBEARANCE, LISBON.
ANY MOMENT NOW, HARKEN IS
GONNA COME AROUND THAT CORNER
WITH AN ANXIOUS EXPRESSION
ON HIS FACE
BECAUSE SOMEONE HAS RUN OFF.
ANY MOMENT NOW.
WAIT.
ANY MOMENT.
[sighs]
NOTHING.
IF YOU JUST GET--
[whack]OW!
OW!
[Patrick] OW. WHOO!
[high-pitched voice] THAT'S WHAT
I'M TALKING 'BOUT.
HI.
WELL, THIS WAS ALL A HOAX?
WELL, "HOAX" IS A LITTLE STRONG.
UH, MORE OF A RUSE, A GAMBIT.
THE IMPORTANT THING IS
WE CAUGHT THE KILLER.
RIGHT? THAT'S WHAT'S IMPORTANT.THAT'S WHAT'S IMPORTANT.
GRIFFIN WELKS, HUH?
NEVER WOULD HAVE CAUGHT HIM
YOUR WAY, AND MY WAY--
CATHARTIC
ANDLIFE-AFFIRMING.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU'RE ON YOUR OWN.
OKAY, THE IMPORTANT THING NOW
IS TO BE CAREFUL
'CAUSE THIS IS
THE REAL THING. OKAY?
ALL RIGHT, LET'S GET THAT BACK
IN THE DEEP FREEZE.
SEE YOU AROUND, BIG DOG.
[door opens]
I WAS SIPHONING OFF SMALL
AMOUNTS OF THE VIRUS MATRIX
AND SELLING IT
ON THE BLACK MARKET.
$300,000 A GRAM.
YEAH.
YEAH, EXACTLY.
I'M IN CHARGE OF KEEPING
INVENTORY, SO IT WAS EASY,
UNTIL HARKEN ARRIVED
TO DO A SPOT CHECK,
AND I HAD TO DO SOMETHING FAST,
SO I SPILLED A FLASK
TO COVER UP
THE MISSING QUANTITY.
KNOWING FULL WELL
ALICIA SEBERG WOULD BE EXPOSED.
[sighs]
SOMEONE HAD TO BE RESPONSIBLE.
I FIGURED
EVERYONE WOULD THINK
THAT SHE'D OPENED THE FLASK
BY ACCIDENT
AND COULDN'T ADMIT TO IT,
'CAUSE SHE WAS LIKE THAT--
COULDN'T BE WRONG.
I'M CURIOUS. THE MONEY
YOU MADE FROM YOUR THEFT--
HOW'D YOU SPEND IT?
I DIDN'T.
I HAVE IT IN TREASURY BONDS
MOSTLY, SOME REAL ESTATE.
MM-HMM,
THAT'S SMART INVESTING.
YOU'LL BE THE RICHEST MAN
IN FOLSOM.
[blinds rattle]
[Patrick exhales deeply]
WHEW. LONG DAY.
OOH.
IT'S CHILLY AROUND HERE.
YOU STILL ANGRY WITH ME?
DUH.[elevator doors open]
OH, CONFESS.
YOU DO FEEL BETTER.
YOU FEEL MUCH MORE ALIVE.
I KNOW YOU DO.
YOU KNOW WHAT
MADE ME FEEL BETTER?
PUNCHING YOU IN THE NOSE.
AH. GLAD TO BE OF SERVICE.
STAY TUNED FOR SCENES
FROM OUR NEXT EPISODE.